Karasuno          Aoba Jousai
(入畑)おお戻たのか及川
Oh, you're back, Oikawa.
足はどうだた
How's your leg?
(及川)ばちりです
もう通常練習もいけます
A-okay.
I can get back to regular practice.
軽い捻挫でしたしね
It was just a light sprain.
Sheesh. You should be more careful.
(入畑)またく気をつけろよ
向こうには
影山出せなんて言といて
We demanded that they play Kageyama, you know.
こちは
正セタじゃないなんて
It'd be really cheap of us if we
didn't play our own starting setter.
頭上がらんだろうが
すいません
I apologize.
Don't push yourself, Oikawa!
(女生徒)及川さん
無理しないでください
(女生徒たち)きゃあ
(女生徒)及川さん
Oikawa!
Say, Kageyama. Who's the pretty boy?
(田中)
影山君あの優男誰ですか
He's really getting on my nerves.
僕とても不愉快です
(澤村)あれが青城の主将だ
(２人)え
That's Seijou's captain.
(影山飛雄)
及川さん超攻撃的セｯタで
Oikawa.
He's a really aggressive setter, and I'm sure he's one of the best attackers on the team on top of that.
攻撃もチムで
トプクラスだと思います
≪影山がここまで言う選手
I can't believe Kageyama's speaking so highly of a player.
あとすごく性格が悪い
お前が言うほどに
Also, he's a total jerk.
That's scary, coming from you!
Might even be worse than Tsukishima.
月島以上かも
それはひどいな
Sounds horrible.
お前の知り合いてことは
北川第一のヤツかよ
You know the guy?
Does that mean he's from Kitagawa First?
はい中学の先輩です
Yeah.
He was my upperclassman in junior high.
≪王様の先輩てことは
The king's upperclassman?
Does that make him a great king?
大王様
やほ飛雄ちゃん久しぶり
Hey there.
Long time no see, Tobio.
飛雄ちゃん久しぶり
おがたね
Long time no see, Tobio.
Episode Seven:
Versus the Great King
It's been forever.
How's ruling your kingdom coming along?
元気に王様やてる
I learned how to serve and block by watching him play.
俺サブとブロクは
あの人を見て覚えました
え
実力は相当です
He's seriously good.
That's who he got the killer serve from?
≪殺人サブの師匠
けど今は試合に集中しろ
But stay focused on the match.
We've gotta win this last set.
最終セト絶対取るぞ
おおうよ
G-Got it.
田中さん威嚇やめて
Quit trying to scare him, Tanaka!
(入畑)とにかく
お前はアプ取てこい
Anyway, go warm up.
いつもより念入りにだぞ
(及川)はい
And be more thorough than usual.
Yes, sir.
(女生徒)きゃあ及川さん
I seriously wanna kill him!
(田中)マジぶ倒す
Aoba Jousai          Karasuno
ねえ及川さん
まだ出ないのかなぁ
Hey, why isn't Oikawa playing yet?
バカウｫミングアｯプしないと
ケガしちゃうんだから
Don't be silly. He has to warm up first,
or else he could get hurt.
All right!
No! Anything but that!
(女生徒)ええそれはダメ
(女生徒)ダメだよ
ち
Right?
Take this!
おらおらおら
ピ
Aoba Jousai          Karasuno
(澤村)≪あと１点≫
(菅原)≪あと１点で
One more point.
One more point...
≪県ベスト４の青城に勝つ≫
...and we'll beat Seijou, one of the top four teams in the prefecture.
(金田一)この調子に乗るな
Don't get full of yourselves, damn it!
しゃあ
(岩泉)金田一ナイス
Good one, Kindaichi!
Don't worry, Tsukishima.
(澤村)ドンマイ月島
ふむ
(及川)
あららピンチじゃないですか
My oh my.
Looks like we're down to the wire.
アプは
ばちりです
How'd your warm up go?
A-okay!
(及川)あとは先輩に任せなさい
(国見)はい
I'll take care of the rest.
Please.
≪出た大王様
(澤村)やめろ
The great king enters the fray!
Cut that out.
こちのｾｯﾀｰが代わるてこと
ううんたぶん
Are we switching setters?
No, I think he's just pinch-serving.
ピンチサバだと思う
(岩泉)及川ナイサ
Give us a good serve, Oikawa!
(及川)
いくら攻撃力が高くてもさ
You could have all the offensive power in the world,
その攻撃まで繋げなきゃ
意味ないんだよ
but it wouldn't mean a thing if you never got to attack.
(菅原)≪なんだ
What?
He's aiming for Tsukishima?
≪月島狙い
(山口)ツ
(武田)い
Tsukki!
(及川)うんやぱり
途中見てたけど
Yep. I knew it.
I watched some of the match.
You, number six,
６番の君と５番の君
う
and you, number five...
レシブ苦手でしょ
１年生かな
You suck at receiving, don't you? First-years, I take it?
≪影山の
いやそれ以上の威力に加えて
His serve is as powerful as Kageyama's—
no, maybe even more.
And he's got the control to direct it wherever he wants.
ほぼ宣言どおりのコスに打つ
コントロル
これが青城の主将≫
This is Seijou's captain.
Another one coming right up.
じゃあもう一本ね
ピ
(山口)ツキ
Tsukki!
All right!
(青城一同)おしゃ
(月島)くそ
Shit.
(澤村)ドンマイ月島
Don't worry about it, Tsukishima!
≪月島いつも意地悪で嫌いだ≫
I hate Tsukishima because he's always such a jerk.
≪けどなんか
But, you know...
Aoba Jousai          Karasuno
(及川)
おあと１点で同点だねぇ
Oh, we'll be tied if we score another point.
Hey, you! Great king!
おいこら大王様
Hit it over here! I'll dig it out!
俺も狙え取てやる
狙えよなめんなよ
Bring it on! Don't you look down on us!
≪大王様
打てこい
Great king?
Quit whining. It's pathetic.
みともないからわめくなよ
なんだと
What was that?!
Amazing how he can still be an ass when we're this close to losing.
≪ピンチのくせして
こんなときもむかつくヤツ≫
Even so...
≪けどけど
(田中･((いいか
Listen up.
バレボルつうのはな
In volleyball,
everyone on your side of the court is your ally, without exception!
ネトのこち側にいる全員
もれなく味方なんだぞ
なんてすばらしい名言
Such wise words!
(澤村)
よし全体的に後ろへ下がれ
Okay.
Get back, all of you.
And Tsukishima, get closer to the sideline.
月島は少しサイドラインに寄れ
(月島)はい
Okay.
よし来い
All right.
Bring it!
ふん
レシブが得意なキｬプテン君が
Net
So the captain, a skilled receiver,
is gonna cover more area himself.
守備範囲を広げるか
でもさ一人で全部は
But, you know, you can't cover the entire court by yourself!
守れないよ
く
Tsukki!
(山口)ツキ
(武田)あんな端こにいるのに
He aimed for him even though
he's standing at the very edge?!
ピンポイントで
(菅原)でもｺﾝﾄﾛｰﾙ重視の分
But because he needed precise control,
this one's weaker than the previous two!
威力はさきより弱いです
上がた
ツキナイス
It's up!
Nice, Tsukki!
お取たね偉い
ちょと取りやすすぎたかな
Wow, he received it. Atta boy.
Maybe I made it a bit too easy for him.
But this is our chance to score.
でもこちの
チャンスボルなんだよね
Damn it.
A golden opportunity.
ほらおいしいおいしい
チャンスボルだ
Put it away, guys.
きちり決めなよお前ら
(矢巾)オライ
I got this!
This is bad. Our current rotation is the one with the shortest blockers.
≪まずいな今はブロクに
いちばん高さがないﾛｰﾃｰｼｮﾝだ≫
(矢巾)金田一
Kindaichi!
≪よし
完全にブロク振り切
Good. I shook off the blockers—
What's that midget doing here?!
(金田一)≪このチビなんで
上がた
ナイスワンタチ
It went up.
Good job making contact!
Now's our chance!
(澤村)チャンスボル
クソが
Why, you little...
Now I'm gonna swat you away!
今度は
俺がたたき落としてやるよ
≪一歩一瞬
ほんの少しでも遅れれば
A step, a second...
Once this guy steals the march on you, you can never catch up to him.
もうこいつには追いつけない≫
The only thing that can...
≪追いつけるのは
is the ball!
ボルだけだ
Aoba Jousai          Karasuno
何今の
コトの端こから一瞬で
What just happened?
He went from one side of the court to the other in a flash.
スパイカの手に
吸い込まれるようなトス
That set looked like it got sucked into the spiker's hand.
Hell yeah!
(田中)よしゃ
(澤村)整列
はぁ
Line up!
んどうしたんですか
すんごい
What's wrong?
That was incredible!
ああそか先生は
日向と影山の攻撃見るのは
Oh, right.
Today's your first time seeing Hinata and Kageyama's quick attacks in action.
今日が初ですもんね
すごいでしょ
Amazing, right?
もうすごいつうか
怖いつうかあ
Actually, I don't know if I should call it amazing or scary.
(一同)お願いします
します
Please give us your thoughts!
Something like a critique, sir.
(菅原)先生なんか講評とか
(武田)あそそうか
O-Oh, right.
えと僕はまだ
I still don't know much about volleyball,
バレボルに関して素人だけど
何か
but...
even I could tell something incredible was going on here.
何かすごいことが起こてるんだ
てことは分かたよ
(２人)ん
(武田)新年度になて
A new school year began, some great first-years joined us,
すごい１年生が入てきて
and things didn't go too well at first,
初めは
ひと筋縄ではいかなくて
but I think I realized something today.
だけど今日分かた気がする
バラバラだたら
なんてことない
Alone, they might be nothing special,
一人と一人が出会うことで
化学変化を起こす
but when certain people come together, they form something far greater than the sum of their parts.
今この瞬間もどこかで
Even as we speak, there might be encounters taking place that could change the world.
世界を変えるような出会いが
生まれていて
It could be anywhere—like in a faraway country,
それは遠い遠い国の
どこかかもしれない
地球の裏側かもしれない
or maybe on the other side of the Earth.
Or they could be taking place in the remote
countryside of a tiny island country in the Far East—
もしかしたら東の小さな島国の
北の片田舎のごく普通の高校の
in the perfectly average volleyball team of a perfectly normal high school.
ごく普通の
バレボル部かもしれない
Watching the match, I felt like something like that had happened at Karasuno.
そんな出会いがここで
烏野であたんだと思た
根拠なんかないけど
信じないよりはずといい
I have nothing to back this belief up,
but I still think it's much better than not believing.
きとこれから
君らは強く強くなるんだな
I'm sure you guys will grow much, much stronger.
ごめんちょと
ポエミだた引いた
Sorry! Was that too flowery?! Did you get weirded out?!
いやいやいやいや
そんなことないです
N-No! Of course not!
あざす
(一同)あざす
Thank you.
S-Sure.
(武田)ああうん
≫金田一
Kindaichi.
(金田一)((俺たちはもう
あいつには限界なんです))
We've had it with that guy!
((いくら
個人の攻撃力が高くても
No matter how good an offensive weapon he is,
he's clearly hurting the team!
明らかに
チムの足を引張てます))
(監督)((はぁ
(金田一)((正直いない方が助かる))
Frankly,
we'd be much better off without him.
お
(金田一)謝たりすんなよ
Don't you dare apologize!
俺も謝んねぇ
おう
I'm not gonna apologize either!
'Kay.
To me, you're still gonna be an oppressive king,
お前は俺ん中ではこれからも
横暴な王様でむかつくヤツで
a jerk, and the guy I wanna destroy most of all!
最高にぶ倒したい相手だ
おう
'Kay.
(金田一)だから謝んな
おう
So don't you dare apologize!
'Kay.
I'm not gonna make up with you.
(金田一)仲直りなんかしねぇ
別にもともと仲よくねぇしな
Not like we used to be friends, anyway.
'Kay.
おう
(金田一)そんで次は絶対に
And next time,
俺たちが勝つ
we'll win for sure!
次も
≫
Next time...
Toilet, toilet!
Who am I?
A future ace, that's who!
Shit, this is one of those situations. You know, bad blood and all that.
≪やべぇこれあれだ
なんか因縁的なあれだ≫
Something tells me I shouldn't get involved.
≪入ていちゃいけない空気だ≫
金田一
Kindaichi.
次戦うときも勝つのは俺たちだ
We'll be the ones to win next time too.
(国見)ん何話してたの
What were you two talking about?
(金田一)
あいつ｢俺たち｣て言たよ
He just said "we."
泣いた
(金田一)いつも｢俺が俺が｣て
Are those tears I see?
Hell no! Just go use the toilet already!
The same guy who used to go "I, my, me"
all the time, like he was fighting a lone battle.
一人で戦てるみたいな言い方
してたくせに
Don't try to change the topic, bro.
Screw you, Hinata!
≪日向ボケェ
(金田一)くそ
Shit.
なんか悔しいな
This is hard to take.
バシ
あだなんだよ
What was that for?
Thank you very much!
(烏野･青城一同)
ありがとうございました
(澤村)武田先生は
ああ言てくれたけど
Mr. Takeda sang our praises,
but honestly speaking, we still desperately lack something required to take Seijou on
正直及川のいる青城と
真向勝負で戦て勝つためには
まだ決定的に足りないものがある
and beat them with Oikawa playing the whole match.
(及川)おおさすがキャプテン
Now that's a captain for you.
(一同)あ
(及川)ちゃんと分かてるねぇ
He knows what he's talking about.
出たな大王様
The great king showed up!
(田中)なんだこら
なんの用だ
Got a problem?
What do you want?
(田中)やんのかこら
やんのかこら
You wanna go?
(及川)そんな邪険にしないでよ
No need to be so hostile.
ちちゃい君
え
You, the little one.
That play you pulled off at the end with the block and the broad jump was incredible.
最後のワンタチとブロド
すごかたね
えあえへへへ
次は最初から全力でやろうね
あ
Next time, let's go all out right from the start.
(及川)まだセトアプは
見せてなかたし
I didn't get to show you how I set, after all.
あそうそうもちろん
サブも磨いておくからね
Oh, right.
I'll make sure to improve my serve too.
≪そうだ本当なら
Oh yeah.
あのサブが
最初から炸裂するんだ≫
Normally, that serve would be unleashed right from the start.
(及川)君らの攻撃は
確かにすごかたけど
Your offense certainly is great,
but if you guys don't get better at receiving, you'll soon hit the glass ceiling.
レシブがグズグズじゃあ
すぐに限界が来るんじゃない
強烈なサブ打てくるヤツは
何も俺だけじゃないしね
I'm not the only one who's got a powerful serve, you know.
インハイ予選はもうすぐだ
ちゃんと生き残てよ
The interhigh prelims are coming up soon.
Don't get knocked out.
俺はこの
Because I want to take this oh-so-precious junior of mine on, setter-on-setter, in an official match and destroy him!
クソかわいい後輩を
公式戦で同じセタとして
正々堂々
たたき潰したいんだからさ
レレシブなら特訓する
(月島)おい放せ
We'll train extra-hard to receive!
Hey, let me go.
レシブは一朝一夕で
上達するもんじゃないよ
You don't get better at receiving overnight.
キャプテン君は
分かてると思うけどね
Though I suppose your captain knows that already.
大会までもう時間はない
どうするのか楽しみにしてるね
You don't have much time left.
I look forward to seeing what you come up with.
き気にしないでください
あの人ああやて
D-Don't let him get to you.
He just likes to mess with people, is all.
人をひかき回すのが
好きなだけなんです
(澤村)ふふふふ
あ
確かに
インタハイ予選まで時間はない
Sure, there's not much time left until the interhigh prelims,
けど
そろそろ戻てくる頃なんだ
but he'll be back soon.
あ
何がですか
Who?
(澤村)烏野の守護神
Karasuno's guardian angel!
≪烏野の守護神≫
Karasuno's guardian angel?
Haikyuu !!
(岩泉)
影山なんかすごくなてたな
Kageyama showed quite the transformation, didn't he?
うん空回てた天才が
Totally.
Now that the prodigy who was spinning his wheels has found the perfect outlet for his talents,
才能の行き場を
見つけちゃたんだから
もう凡人には
かなわないんじゃない
plebeians are no match for him.
(岩泉)へえ
お前でもかなわないのかよ
Does that include you?
At setting, yeah.
トスはね
トス回しで飛雄にかなうヤツ
I don't think there's a single setter in this prefecture who can distribute the ball as well as he does.
県内にはいないんじゃないまあ
サブもブロｯクもスパイクも
He's not as good as me at serving, blocking, or spiking, though.
負けないけどねあ痛
トスも負けないて言えよ
クソ及川
Damn it, Oikawa! Don't just admit his sets are better than yours!
And you call yourself a setter?
てめぇセタだろうが
だてほんとのことだもん
But it's true!
だからこそ
レシブを崩すんでしょ
That's exactly why we need to break their defense down.
どんなにトスがすごくたて
It doesn't matter how good their setter is if they don't get him the ball.
ボルがセタに返んなきゃ
意味ないんだから
I hope we get to play Karasuno in an official match.
公式戦で烏野と当たたら
I wanna throw their defense for a loop, give them no chances to make any sets, and then smugly say to them,
レシブ
めちゃくちゃに乱して
まともにトス回しする機会なんか
与えずに
"Having a star on your team doesn't mean you'll win. But don't worry about it!"
｢一人だけうまくたて
勝てないんだよドンマイ｣て
言いたい言いたい
I wanna say it so bad!
え何だて
天才とかむかつくじゃん
What? Don't prodigies piss you off?
(岩泉)俺は女にきゃあきゃあ
言われてるヤツの方がむかつく
Guys who girls fawn over piss me off even more!
(及川)痛ひがみは
みともないぞ岩ちゃん
Ow!
Jealous much, Iwa? That's pathetic!
Oww!
Quit messing around or the Coach will get mad at you.
(花巻)おい遊んでと
コチに怒られぞ
That hurts, Iwa!
(澤村)よしじゃあ
軽く掃除して終了お疲れした
Let's clean up the place a little, and that'll be that.
Well done, boys!
Thank you!
(一同)した
おい
Hey!
先生今日は
ありがとうございました
Thanks for today, sir.
Don't mention it. You all did great today.
いやいやみんなお疲れさま
僕びくりしたよ
I was amazed you actually went and beat the Aoba Jousai!
あの青葉城西高校に
勝ちゃうんだから
でもまだ足りないんです
But we're not quite there yet.
今日向と影山が
機能してるおかげで
We're somehow scoring points
thanks to Hinata and Kageyama,
なんとか攻撃は決まてますが
日向が
ブロクに捕まりだしたり
but if Hinata were to be caught by the blockers
Forget about mopping, Hinata. Go home.
or our defense broken down like today,
今日みたいに
レシブ崩されたりしたら
Look at that, Tsukki.
なす術がなくなります
we'd be in deep trouble.
Oh wow.
それに
そういう状況になたとき
And if we were to find ourselves in such a situation,
俺が
監督とかコチみたいな立場で
I'm not sure I'd be able to lead the team like a coach would.
指揮とれるかどうか
なるほど
Right.
あすみません先生が
力不足とかじゃなくてですね
I'm sorry!
I don't mean to say you're not good enough!
あはは
分かてる分かてる
I know.
Don't worry. I'll get you a coach.
指導者の方は僕に任せてくれ
当てはあるんだ
I know where to go.
えそうなんですか
それて
Really?
Who is it?
Foot of the Slope
I've asked plenty of times before,
and I've yet to get a positive reply,
(武田)何度かお願いしてて
まだ了解はもらえてないけど
きとなんとかしてみせる
but I'll make it happen somehow.
じゃああとここ任せていいかな
あはい
Could you take care of the rest for today?
Yes, sir.
ななんか武ちゃんが頼もしい
うん
F-For some reason, Take seems really reliable right now.
Yeah.
Equipment Room
What the heck?
This mop doesn't look safe. Can I throw it away?
このモプ危ないから
捨てちゃてもいいですか
(菅原)あ
いいんだそれはいいんだ
Oh, don't worry. It's fine.
直せばまた使えるだろ
We can still use it if we get it fixed.
(縁下)お疲れした
(成田･木下)した
Dismissed!
Thank you!
Foot of the Slope
(繋心)中華まん
Chinese buns?
さきサカ部が
買てたのが最後だ
The soccer team just bought the last ones.
それで今日はもう終了
We're sold out for the day.
But I'm starving!
腹減た
(田中)職務怠慢だ
Do your job, lazybones!
うるせぇささと帰て
ちゃんとした飯を食え
Shaddup!
Go home and eat a proper meal already!
You won't build any muscle otherwise!
Catch.
おお
(３人)あざす
Thank you!
(繋心)ちゃんと飯食えよ
(田中･日向)ひゃほい
Make sure to eat dinner.
☎
あいあい
Coming.
(繋心)あい坂ノ下商店
Hello, this is Foot of the Slope.
またあんたかよ
Not you again.
(田中)それにしてもよ
あの優男のサブすごかたな
All said and done,
that pretty boy had an amazing serve.
We would've been in deep shit if we had to deal with that the entire match.
最初からあれやられてたら
ヤバかたぜ
I guess we should've expected as much from Kageyama's upperclassman...
さすが影山と同じ中学の先輩
あれ
Wait, why'd you even join Karasuno?
ていうか影山て
なんで烏野にいるんだけ
ん
(田中)県内一の強豪つたら
The strongest school in this prefecture is Shiratorizawa.
やぱ白鳥沢だろ
しらとり
Shiratori?
(田中)
白鳥沢つう県ではダントツ
Shiratorizawa. By far the best team in the prefecture,
and a powerhouse that's among the top eight in the country.
全国でも必ず８強には食い込む
強豪校があんだよ
Wow.
落ちました白鳥沢
落ちた
I didn't get into Shiratorizawa.
You what?!
白鳥沢から推薦来なかたし
They didn't give me a recommendation,
so I took the general entrance exam and failed.
一般で受けて落ちました
試験が意味不明でした
It was Greek and Hebrew to me.
(澤村)
あそこは普通に入ろうとしたら
Yeah, I hear it's really hard to get in the normal way.
超難関だもんなぁ
(月島)へえ
Oh, so the king isn't very good at studies.
王様
勉強は大したことないんだね
See you tomorrow.
ち
でなんで烏野
Why Karasuno, then?
まさか
お前も小さな巨人に憧れて
Did you wanna be like the Little Giant too?
引退した烏養監督が
戻てくるて聞いたから
Because I heard Coach Ukai was coming out of retirement.
うかい
(田中)無名だた烏野を
Ukai?
The miracle worker who led no-name Karasuno to the spring nationals!
｢春高｣の全国大会まで導いた名将
へえ
(田中)烏野の烏養て名前が
もう有名だたよな
"Karasuno's Ukai" became famous all across the nation.
凶暴な烏飼てる監督だつて
They called him a coach who led a group of violent crows.
He coached the current upperclassmen a little last year.
２３年生は
去年少しだけ指導受けたけど
すげぇスパルタだたぞ
He was a real hardass.
Why do you look envious?
(菅原)
なんで羨ましそうなんだよ
Coach Ukai was officially gonna
come out of retirement, but then...
烏養監督は本格的な復帰が
決まてたんだけど
((倒れた
((今のとこ復帰の予定はないんだ))
He got hospitalized?!
He doesn't plan on coming back anytime soon. Sorry.
((すまん))
It doesn't really matter what school I'm in, though.
けど別にどの学校に入たて
戦う相手は同じ高校生
I'll be facing high schoolers just like me.
勝てない理由なんてない
(田中)負け惜しみはよせ
There's no reason why I can't win.
Don't be a sore loser now.
カコつけて言てもムダだ
ぷ
Acting cool isn't gonna help.
You're wrong! And I'm not trying to act cool!
違いますよ
カコもつけてません
実際に今日
４強に勝たじゃないですか
We did actually beat a top four team today, didn't we?
Well, yeah.
(田中)
まあなあの青城に２対１
We beat Seijou 2-1.
俺もフリで決められたし
日向の囮のおかげだな
And I was able to score freely. Guess we have Hinata to thank for being such a great decoy.
ああざす
(田中)本人的にはどうだたよ
Th-Thanks!
Anyway, how did you like your debut?
デビュ戦は
あ
(田中)まあ１セト目
盛大にやらかしたけどな
Though, well, you did screw up spectacularly in the first set.
You conceded as many points as you scored, so you'd better not be satisfied with it.
得点と同じぐらい
失点もしてんだから満足すんなよ
(菅原)
なんでそういうこと言うんだよ
Why do you have to say things like that?!
That's right.
そうなんだよ俺たちには
まだいろいろ足りてなくて
We're lacking in a lot of ways,
and we only barely managed to win today.
今日の勝利もギリギリだた
いいぱい練習します
I-I'll train a bunch!
あうん
個人のレベルアｯプも大事だな
O-Okay.
Individual improvements are important too.
But right now, Karasuno's badly short on hands.
けど今の烏野には根本的に
メンバが足りてないんだよ
ん
そうですよね
Yeah.
守備の要のリベロそれと
We need a defensive cornerstone—a libero,
and an ace spiker who can take on three blockers by himself.
１人で敵の３枚ブロクと
勝負できるエススパイカ
エエスなら俺が
I call that!
I told you already! You're the greatest decoy!
だからおめぇは
最強の囮だつてんだろ
でも守護神が戻てくるて
言てましたよね
But didn't you say our "guardian angel"
would be back soon?
(澤村)うん
(菅原)うちは強豪じゃないけど
Yeah.
We're no powerhouse, but we're not all that weak either.
特別弱くもない今までだて
This team's had some talented players during my time here,
優秀な人材はいたはずなのに
その力をちゃんと繋げてなかた
but we never managed to put their strengths together.
でもまたみんながそろて
But if all of us come together again,
add you first-years to the equation,
そこに
１年生の新戦力も加わて
and put everything we have together...
その戦力
ちゃんと全部繋げたら
夏のインタハイ
...then the summer interhigh—
全国が
ただの遠くの目標じゃなく
taking the national throne—
won't just be some faraway goal.
現実につかめるものに
きとなる
I'm certain that it'll be within our reach!
夏のインタハイ
聞いたことある
I've heard about the summer interhigh!
But this guy you say is coming back...
けどそのこれから戻てくる人は
今までどうしてたんですか
Where has he been all this while?
１週間の自宅謹慎と
約１か月の部活禁止だたんだ
He was suspended for a week and banned from club activities for about a month.
えふ不良不良
(田中)違ぇよあれはな
Is he a delinquent?
Hell no!
He's just... a little too passionate, is all.
ちょと熱すぎるだけなんだよ
いいヤツなんだよマジで
He's a seriously nice guy.
≪田中さんに熱すぎるて
言われるとかどんだけだ≫
I can't believe Tanaka of all people is
calling someone else "too passionate."
(田中)それにあいつはな
That's not all.
He's Karasuno's one and only prodigy.
烏野で唯一天才と呼べる選手だ
ま今はクソ生意気な影山が
入てきたから
Though I guess he's not the "one and only" anymore, now that we have the super-cocky Kageyama too.
唯一じゃなくなたけどな
へへ
Call him "sir" when he comes back, Hinata.
(澤村)そいつが戻てきたら
先輩て呼んでやれよ日向
田中みたく
バカ喜びすると思うから
You'll make him stupidly happy, just like Tanaka.
"Stupidly"?
バカとか
Guardian angel, huh?
≪守護神かどんな人かなぁ≫
I wonder what he's like.
≪(田中)置いてくぞ
あはい
We're gonna leave you behind!
Coming!
≪お当たる
It's gonna hit!
おい
邪魔すんなボケ日向ボケェ
Don't get in my way, Hinatard!
今当たたかもしんねぇのに
取た俺取た
That could've hit the target, you know!
Did I get it? Did I dig it out?
取れてねぇよボケ
ホムランだろ
Hell no, jackass! You knocked it out of the park!
取てくる
アホ
I'll go get it back.
Idiot.
I got it this time.
≪おしゃ今度こそ
≪勢いも回転も全部殺して
He killed all the speed and spin,
and returned the ball to where the setter would be.
返球はきちり
セタのいる位置≫
≪完璧なレシブ≫
That was a perfect receive.
お俺より小さい
Y-You're shorter than me?
Next Episode Preview
What the hell just happened?
なんだなんだなんだあれ
ズザキュて現れたぞ
He showed up like "zoom"!
And then he received like "bam" and sent it back like "whoosh."
ドと受けてフワて返したな
なんかグワてきた
Now I'm all like "whoa."
Well, it's not like I can't understand what you're saying, but...
(澤村)まあ
伝わらなくもないんだけどさ
Episode Eight:
The One They Call "Ace"
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
"The One They Call 'Ace.'"